Milan Barande

Senior Front End Developer

I am a web and mobile product-minded front-end developer with 7 years of experience. I also enjoy working on the back-end and on the implementation of DevOps practices. I care about good UX, performance, security and accessibility.

I like functional programming and producing simple, robust, and well tested code. I'm always eager to learn new technologies and also enjoy teaching junior developers. I can work in English, French, or German, and am currently learning Dutch.

Amsterdam, 1073 BW +33631272431 milan.barande@gmail.com LinkedIn Personal Website GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Club Med - Remote (Amsterdam)

React Native Developer (My Club Med)

January 2023 - Present

- Contributed to the remake of the "My Club Med" app with a new design and refreshed features for better user experience, leading to an increase in the average rating from 2.5 to 4+ stars on the French App Store (main market).
- Refactored core application modules and improved test coverage by 50% through automated testing frameworks; enhanced maintainability led to a 30% reduction in bug reports and increased deployment frequency.
- Automated the release process and the generation of changelogs connected to our ticketing system.
- Update of major project dependencies, including Expo and React-Native, resulting in improved app performance metrics by 20% and enhanced user experience through faster load times (Firebase metrics).

Club Med - Paris, France

Lead Front End Engineer (www.clubmed.com)

September 2022 - January 2023

- Led the 'My Account' squad, responsible for a React application and its GraphQL API.
- Executed a comprehensive bug-fixing initiative, addressing over 20 user-reported issues, resulting in a 50% reduction in customer complaints related to booking functionalities.
- Designed and launched a localized adaptation of clubmed.com exempt of e-commerce features and focusing solely on enabling users to access their booking information.

CORE SKILLS

JavaScript TypeScript

React

React Native

Expo

NextJS

NodeJS GraphQL

Redux

Git

DevOps (CI/CD,

automation)

Jest

Puppeteer

Maestro

EDUCATION

Le Wagon

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp

Summer 2017

Montréal, Canada

Université de Montréal

• Cleaned up the typing (Flow) and refactored the codebase for enhanced efficiency and readability.

Parfums Christian Dior - Paris, France

Front End Developer (www.dior.com)

January 2021 - July 2022

- Engineered a unique animated user interface for Dior perfume bottles, allowing customers to select from different wood types for the hood and customize engravings.
- Developed an innovative animated navigation interface for dior.com's mobile site, enabling seamless location tracking that improved user experience.
- Created a tailored SSO solution for the Line app, facilitating targeted advertising efforts in Japan, Taiwan, and Korea; increased ad engagement rates by 40% within the first three months post-launch.
- Collaborated with external consultants to assess website compliance with ADA standards; achieved a significant milestone by rectifying over 80% of identified accessibility barriers, ensuring a more inclusive online presence.

Neuroscience Postgraduate Program

2016-2017

Montréal, Canada

Université de Montréal

Kinesiology B. Sc. 2013-2016

Montréal, Canada

Christian Dior Couture - Paris, France

Front End Developer (www.dior.com)

April 2019 - January 2021

- Revamped the basket and checkout interfaces for enhanced UX on both desktop and mobile, and enabled easy customization of the checkout page per locale by our contributors.
- Implemented specialized features for the Japanese market, enhancing user experience with address autocomplete based on postcode, different payment options, and other culturally relevant design elements.
- Added options to customize delivery with a gift box and a personalized message.
- Launched an intuitive returns interface that allows customers to select different sizes or variations effortlessly.
- Refactored the project architecture into a monorepo and converted the code base from Flow to TypeScript.
- Constructed a robust GraphQL API to streamline communication between four backend services.

Le Wagon - Paris, France

Workshop Instructor

Decembre 2017 - Novembre 2019

Occasionally hosted the following coding workshops for Le Wagon at various locations of the Paris startup ecosystem such as Station F:

- Creating a landing page with HTML and CSS (Introduction to Web Development)
- Introduction to JavaScript
- Introduction to React

Bluenove - Paris, France

Junior Frontend Developer

Septembre 2017 - April 2019

- Developed the V2 of Assembl, a collective intelligence platform facilitating discussions among thousands of participants to generate new ideas, vote on the best ones, and produce a final product.
- Designed a debate synthesis page that incorporated a scroll spy feature, enhancing user navigation through the various text sections.
- Developed a multi-sentiment reaction feature for the debates messages.
- Contributed to the design of the voting page, enabling Assembl debate participants to vote for their favorite propositions from the initial debating phase.